# KURTBAUER

# SOFTWARE ENGINEER

#### SKILLS

Active Record , Android Studio , APIs , Bootstrap , BCrypt , Charles Proxy , CSS/HTML , Gatsby.js , GIT , NPM , JavaScript , jQuery , JSON , JIRA , PostgreSQL , Rails , React , Redux , React-Native , Ruby , SemanticUl , Sinatra , SQL , Tachyons.js , TDD , Thunk , xCode

#### CONTACT

Phone: **954** . **547** . **5395** 

Location: Brooklyn, NY

Email:

kurtbauer55@protonmail.com

LinkedIn:

http://linkedin.com/in/kurt-bauer

Portfolio:

http://kurtbauer.netlify.com

Github:

http://github.com/krtb

Blog:

http://dev.to/krtb

Blog

https://medium.com/@kurt\_bauer

Twitter:

http://twitter.com/kurtbauer

#### EDUCATION

**University of Florida - Gainesville**Major in English Literature,
Minor in Linguistics

**BACHELOR OF ARTS** (2012-2015)

### Flatiron School - Manhattan

Full-Stack: JavaScript, React, Redux, Ruby, Rails (using JSON API), HTML5/CSS, PostgreSQL/SQL, Sinatra

SOFTWARE ENGINEERING (2018)

#### ABOUT ME

A multilingual professional with web front-end, back-end, and mobile experience. I cater to a dynamic range of users, increasing company reach with the help of my technical and interpersonal skills. I speak both Spanish and German fluently, allowing me to connect and understand a wider range of company customers and staff.

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

## Freelance(2019 - present) Small Projects and Portfolio Development

Working to create personal projects while consuming new tech stacks

- Working with Node.js, Express, MongoDB
- Further developing personal app with ProPublica API

#### Software Engineer(2018 - 2019) EachScape, Manhattan

A cloud based environment to build and manage native mobile applications, also maintains E! News app.

- Worked with React Native to maintain the E! News apps for ios/android, tracked tickets on JIRA, version control with GIT
- Created a client cataloguing web app with React and EachScape Database
- Used HTML/CSS & JavaScript to create reusable components for EachScape SDK platform

# **Project Manager**(2017 - 2018) **Office Depot Corporate Offices, Boca Raton** An office supply retailing company.

- Implemented discovery of data center servers and network gear
- Established content management database to improve system intearitu
- Migrated company from Google Apps to Microsoft O365 in 6 months

#### MY PROJECTS

**Fabrikant Jewelers** (fabrikant.eachscape.com) A tool for the company to store client information.

- Tech: React.js/Redux, EachScape API, EachScape DB
- Create, delete, update and view clients & their significant others.

**InforMee** (https://youtu.be/HXDGytM1vys) A political app to follow bills after they're introduced into the Senate.

- Tech: React/Redux, Rails, PostgreSQL, ProPublica API
- Users can view, store, and search for new bills in the House of Representatives.

**Crypto\_Crash** (http://github.com/krtb/Crypto\_Crash) CLI role playing game, where you're an ametuer crypto trader looking to escape to Canada.

- Tech: Ruby, Sinatra, SQLite3, Active Record, TTY Prompt, Pastel
- Earn crypto worth \$5,000, while encountering a deteriorating global society that causes you to sell off your precious assets.